vivatic.com 2019-07-21

# Privacy Policy | Vivatic

**PRIVACY NOTICE**

**You have certain rights in relation to your data, including the right to object to processing based on legitimate interests. At any time, you can exercise your rights by emailing us at[dataprotection@mvfglobal.com](mailto:dataprotection@mvfglobal.com). For further details about our processing and your rights, please see below.**

**CONTENTS**

• About our site  
• How our site works  
• About us  
• What we don’t do with your data  
• What data we collect, and how  
• How we use your data  
• Cookies  
• Transferring your data  
• Storing your data  
• Legal grounds  
• Your rights  
• Contacting us  
• Changes to this notice

**ABOUT OUR SITE**

Through our site, people can register to access, view and participate in online surveys and other earning opportunities (“ **Earning Opportunities** ”).

The service that our site provides is to connect people with providers of Earning Opportunities (e.g. market research companies) (“ **Service Providers** ”).

**HOW OUR SITE WORKS**

If you’d like to access, view and participate in Earning Opportunities, please register to use our site by completing our webform on the homepage. 

Unfortunately, if you’re under 16 years old, you won’t be able to our site.

Once you’ve registered to use our site, you will receive a welcome email from us.  
Whenever you wish to view available Earning Opportunities, you simply need to log in to your membership account (“ **Account** ”), using your email address and password (as explained below). All available Earning Opportunities will be shown in your Account dashboard. 

If you expressly select an Earning Opportunity, you will be taken to the Service Provider’s website to participate in the same. Please note that the Service Provider’s own privacy notice and terms of use will apply. 

At any time, you can close your Account.

**ABOUT US**

Vivatic is a brand of Marketing VF Limited ( **“MVF”, “we”, “us”, “our”** ).

MVF is a company registered in England and Wales (company number: 06951544), whose registered office address is at Imperial Works, Perren Street, London NW5 3ED, United Kingdom.

For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”), Marketing VF Limited is the controller in relation to your data. We are registered as a controller with the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) under registration number Z1995728. You can confirm our registration here: [www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/ "www.ico.org.uk")

**WHAT WE DON’T DO WITH YOUR DATA**

Before confirming what data we collect, and why, here’s what we definitely don’t do with your data, unless clearly set out in this notice.

• We don’t share it with anyone else.  
• We don’t use it for any purpose (including retargeting, commingling across multiple advertisers’ campaigns or allowing piggybacking or redirecting with tags), except on an aggregate and anonymous basis, and only to assess the performance and effectiveness of our advertising campaigns.  
• We don't use it to build, append to, edit, influence or augment user profiles, including profiles associated with any mobile device identifier or other unique identifiers that identify any particular user, browser, computer or device.  
• We don’t transfer it (including any anonymous, aggregate or derived data) to any advertising network, advert exchange, data broker, or other advertising or monetisation-related service.

**WHAT DATA WE COLLECT, AND HOW**

If you register to use our site (as described above), our webform will ask you for your first and last names, and email address. It will also ask you for a password, which you will need whenever you access your Account.

Once you’ve registered to use our site, you can provide us with further information in the profile section of your Account. It’s entirely up to you what information you provide in this section, and you don’t have to provide any further information at all if you don’t want to.

From time to time, we may change our webform and the profile section. It will always be clear from the webform and profile section what information we’re requesting.

For us to pay you for Earning Opportunities that you have completed, you need a Paypal account. We will ask you to confirm your Paypal account by logging into your account through our site. When you do this, Paypal will confirm your email address, country, and post code. We do not use this information for any other purpose, only to confirm your Paypal account. 

We also store and share Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, as explained below. Every computer or device has an IP address – a unique number – which enables it to communicate with other computers and devices over the Internet. 

Additionally, we might collect data about you if you contact us, or we contact you, by email, telephone or post. 

**HOW WE USE YOUR DATA**

We use your data (described above) in the following ways.

**To enable you to access your Account, and view and participate in Earning Opportunities**

As explained above, you will need your email address and password each time you access your Account. This is to ensure that your Account remains secure.

All available Earning Opportunities will be shown in your Account dashboard.

If you choose to provide us with further information in the profile section of your Account, we may use this additional information to find and show you Earning Opportunities that are most relevant to you and your profile.

If you expressly select an Earning Opportunity, you will be taken to the Service Provider’s website to participate in the same. Please note that the Service Provider’s own privacy and cookies notices and terms of use will apply. Please read these carefully.

We store IP addresses so that we know which country you’re based in, and we can therefore show you our site in your local language.

**To create custom and lookalike/similar audiences**

We like to work with Facebook, Google and other platforms (“ **Platforms** ”) to reach out to you with adverts. We also like to use Platforms to reach out to other people who might like to use our site.

We do this in two ways. In both cases, your data, along with other data, is used to create a custom audience and/or a lookalike/similar audience. Whenever an audience is shared with a Platform, the data is first hashed and pseudonymised, meaning that any data within the audience that could identify a person is replaced with an artificial identifier. So, the process is secure. Also, we don’t share more data than we need to for the purpose of creating the audience.

• **Custom audience** – A custom audience is a list of existing members of our site (“ **Existing Members** ”). From time to time, we share this with Platforms. As explained above, the data is first hashed and pseudonymised. The Platform uses this audience to show our Existing Members our adverts.  
• **Lookalike/similar audience** – A lookalike/similar audience is an audience created by the Platform. From time to time, we share with Platforms a list of Existing Members. The Platform uses this list to find and create lookalikes – i.e. other Platform users who have similar characteristics to the Existing Members – to which it shows our adverts. Again, as explained above, the data is first hashed and pseudonymised.

As we explain below, at any time, you may object to such activity by emailing us at [dataprotection@mvfglobal.com](mailto:dataprotection@mvfglobal.com).

**Working with suppliers**

We work with a number of suppliers, who process data on our behalf. These include cloud storage providers and email service providers. We have appropriate contracts in place with such suppliers to ensure the protection and confidentiality of data.

**COOKIES**

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. At the bottom of this policy, we have included a table, setting out what cookies we use, and the purposes for which we use them.

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "http://www.aboutcookies.org") or [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "http://www.allaboutcookies.org").

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

**TRANSFERRING YOUR DATA**

We may transfer your data outside the European Economic Area (the “EEA“).

Some of those countries (e.g. Canada, USA) have a European Commission adequacy decision, which means they are considered to offer an adequate level of data protection. 

Other countries do not have the same level of legal protection as countries in the EEA, or with an adequacy decision. If we do transfer your data in this way, we will take steps to ensure that it is protected to the same levels that apply in the EEA. This may include, for example, ensuring that the organisation receiving the data is registered with the EU-US Privacy Shield (in the case of transfers to the USA), or that we use the EU’s model contract clauses.

**STORING YOUR DATA**

We have a data retention policy, which clearly sets out how long we keep data for, and for what reasons.

We will keep your data only for as long as is necessary to fulfil the purpose/s for which it was collected in the first place, i.e. as set out in this notice.

For example: If you haven’t accessed your Account for a period of 3 years or more, we will delete your Account.

**LEGAL GROUNDS**

This notice sets out (above) how we use your data. Under the GDPR, controllers must have a valid lawful basis for each processing activity that they undertake. This section sets out our lawful basis for each activity.

Activity | Lawful basis under the GDPR | Your rights  
---|---|---  
To enable you to access your Account, and view and participate in Earning Opportunities  
Storing and using IP addresses  
| Legitimate interests | You have the right to object to processing based on legitimate interests  
To create custom and lookalike/similar audiences | Legitimate interests | You have the right to object to processing based on legitimate interests  
  
In each case where we have identified legitimate interests as the legal basis for our processing, we have conducted a legitimate interests assessment.

**YOUR RIGHTS**

Under the GDPR, you have a number of rights. In relation to our site, and the service that we provide, those rights are set out in the table above. We further explain these rights, and your other rights, below.

**Right of access** – You have the right at any time to ask us for a copy of the personal information that we hold about you, and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

**Right of rectification** – If personal information that we hold about you is not accurate or is out of date and requires amendment or correction, you have a right to have the data rectified or completed. 

**Right of erasure** – In certain circumstances, you have the right to request that personal information we hold about you is erased (e.g. if the information is no longer necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or processed).

**Right to object to or restrict processing** – In certain circumstances, you have the right to object to our processing of your personal information. For example, if we are processing your information on the basis of our legitimate interests, and there are no compelling legitimate grounds for our processing which override your rights and interests. 

**Right of data portability** – In certain instances, you have a right to receive any personal information that we hold about you in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format.

**Right to withdraw consent** – In the limited circumstances where you may have provided your consent to the collection, processing and transfer of your personal information for a specific purpose, you have the right to withdraw your consent for that specific processing at any time.

**Exercising your rights**

At any time, you can close your Account.

If you wish to exercise any of your other rights under the GDPR, please email us at [dataprotection@mvfglobal.com](mailto:dataprotection@mvfglobal.com). Alternatively, you can write to us at the address set out above, or inform us if you speak with us on the phone.

Our lead supervisory authority for the processing set out in this notice is the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO). If you are unhappy with how we have processed your data, you have the right to make a complaint to the ICO.

If you are based outside of the UK, or you have a complaint concerning our activities outside of the UK, you may prefer to lodge a complaint with a different Supervisory Authority. A list of relevant authorities can be accessed here <http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080>.

**CONTACTING US**

If you have any questions regarding this notice, or any questions relating to data protection or privacy, you can contact us at [dataprotection@mvfglobal.com](mailto:dataprotection@mvfglobal.com).  
Alternatively, you can write to us at the address set out above.

Cookie | Name | Purpose  
---|---|---  
Vivatic  | has_js  | This cookie remembers if your browser is able to make use of features on our site to provide feedback and validation as you enter your details.  
Vivatic  | SESS* | This cookie is essential to the operation of the website. The data is deleted when you close the browser window.  
|  |   
Google Analytics | _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmv  
_utmz | We use Google Analytics to measure anonymous visitor activity to our site. These cookies collect information about how visitors use our website. We use the information to compile reports and to make improvements. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including where visitors have come to the website from and the pages they visited. 

To opt-out: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout  
  
Universal Analytics (Google) |  _ga  
_gali  
_gat_UA-1036645-1  
_gid | These cookies collect information about how visitors use our website. We use the information to compile reports and to make improvements. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including where visitors have come to the website from and the pages they visited. 

To opt-out: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout  
  
Taboola Retargeting |  | These cookies are used to tailor Taboola adverts to a user’s previous viewing habits. For instance, if you have previously visited our page, you may then see other adverts related to that product or service. Taboola is an ad network that shows sponsored content, usually as links below the article on major news sites.  
Outbrain Retargeting |  | These cookies are used to tailor Outbrain adverts to a user’s previous viewing habits. For instance, if you have previously visited our page, you may then see other adverts related to that product or service. Outbrain is an ad network that shows sponsored content, usually as links below the article on major news sites.  
Adwords Retargeting (Google) |  | These cookies are used to adjust the targeting of our paid search and display advertising to show ads to users who have previously been to our sites and/or engaged with our page such as completing a form. They contain no personal information.  
DoubleClick Retargeting |  | These cookies are used to adjust the targeting of our display advertising to show ads to users who have previously been to our sites and/or engaged with our page such as completing a form. They contain no personal information.  
Taboola Conversion Tracking |  | These cookies measure ad conversions and optimise spend for advertising campaigns served on Taboola.  
Outbrain Conversion Tracking |  | These cookies measure ad conversions and optimise spend for advertising campaigns served on Outbrain.  
Yahoo Conversion Tracking |  | These cookies measure ad conversions and optimise spend for advertising campaigns served on Yahoo Gemini.  
Zemanta Conversion Tracking |  | These cookies measure ad conversions and optimise spend for advertising campaigns served on Zemanta.  
Ligatus/LiquidM Conversion Tracking |  | These cookies measure ad conversions and optimise spend for advertising campaigns served on Ligatus and LiquidM.  
Plista Conversion Tracking |  | These cookies measure ad conversions and optimise spend for advertising campaigns served on Plista.  
Revcontent Conversion Tracking |  | These cookies measure ad conversions and optimise spend for advertising campaigns served on Revcontent.  
EngageYa Conversion Tracking |  | These cookies measure ad conversions and optimise spend for advertising campaigns served on EngageYa.  
Adwords Conversion Tracking |  | These cookies measure when a user has completed an action on site such as completing a form. They contain no personal information.  
Bing Conversion Tracking | UET Tag | These cookies measure when a user has completed an action on site such as completing a form. They contain no personal information.  
DoubleClick Conversion Tracking |  | These cookies measure when a user has completed an action on site such as completing a form. They contain no personal information.  
Facebook Pixel |  | These cookies measure ad conversions, optimise and build audiences for advertising campaigns served on Facebook. 

To opt-out: <https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/>  
  
Nanigans JavaScript Pixel |  | These cookies measure ad conversions and optimise advertising campaigns managed through Nanigans. They contain no personal information. 

To opt-out: <http://www.nanigans.com/privacy-policy/>  
  
Twitter Pixel |  | These cookies measure ad conversions and optimise advertising campaigns served on Twitter. 

To opt-out: [https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tai...](https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads "https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads")  
  
LinkedIn Pixel |  | These cookies measure ad conversions, optimise and build audiences for advertising campaigns served on LinkedIn. 

To opt-out: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy>  
  
Pinterest Tag |  | These cookies are used to track conversions, optimise and build audiences to reach customers on Pinterest. 

To opt-out: <https://help.pinterest.com/en/articles/personalized-ads-pinterest>  
  
Skimlinks |  | Our website receives paid commission on sales of those products or services we write about. In some instances, we use a 3rd Party to enable these affiliate partnerships. 

To opt-out: <https://skimlinks.com/privacy-policy#users>  
  
Amazon Associates |  | These cookies track referral visits to Amazon for which we may earn commission for any eventual purchases.   
Adsense |  | Adsense uses cookies to improve advertising e.g. displaying targeted advertisements and avoiding showing advertisements that the user has already seen. 

These cookies contain no personally identifiable information.   
  
VWO | _vwo  | These cookies are used to help us optimise our sites by running tests and measuring user conversions. It is also used to track user information when visiting the site (e.g. browser and device information).   
HotJar |  | Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behaviour (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click etc) and their devices (in particular device’s IP address, captured and stored only in anonymised form, preferred language settings etc). This enables us to better understand our users’ needs and to optimise this service and experience.  
Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymised user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user.  
To opt out: <https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out>  
  
**CHANGES TO THIS NOTICE**

From time to time, we may update this notice.

Last reviewed: 21 May 2018
